梅尔
Mel.
梅尔 没事吧
Mel, are you okay?
没事
It's okay.
不
No.
- 梅尔 受伤了没有  - 我没事
- Are you hurt? - I'm fine.
你别动 我来处理
那边 快 快去
Go, go.
《英雄联盟:双城之战》
第二季第一集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
她是个了不起的人
She was a great woman.
是一位挚友
A good friend.
没了她 我不知该如何应对这次危机
I don't know how we'll face this crisis without her.
我们竟然差点把自治权交给了
To think we nearly extended sovereignty
犯下这等罪行的禽兽
to the creatures who did this.
肩负着维护秩序的重任
We're charged with imposing order.
可我们却如此的懈怠
And we've been asleep at our posts.
现在我算看清了
Well, my eyes are open.
一天不将底城这帮残党余孽彻底铲除
There will be no more fairy tales of peace
和平就只能化为梦幻泡影
until we scour our basement of its demons.
感谢你对萨罗议员的帮助 母亲
So kind of you to assist Councilor Salo, Mother.
既然我们身陷战争
As we are at war,
我认为请这位久经沙场的老将
I thought it prudent to solicit the advice
指点一二再好不过了
of such an experienced veteran.
还是先解决眼下的问题吧
Let us address the matter at hand.
现在到处人心惶惶 生灵涂炭
Our people are scared, suffering.
得让所有人知道我们能够控制住局面
They need to know their leaders have the situation under control.
直接给他们点颜色瞧瞧
An unprecedented show of force.
派我们的执法官荡平底城
We flood the undercity with Enforcers,
带上海克斯武器
armed with Hextech.
这么做会伤及无辜的平民
Innocents will be caught in the cross fire.
到底要看到多少个 议员被炸得粉身碎骨
How many more councilors have to be blown to pieces
你才肯醒悟啊
before you wake up?
我们现在腹背受敌
We are under siege.
她为什么会在这儿
What is she doing here?
吉拉曼恩执法官亲眼目睹了袭击
Officer Kiramman witnessed the attack firsthand.
她能够证实这是一个 精神错乱者的个人行为
She confirmed this was the act of a single deranged individual.
金克丝
Jinx.
希尔科死了
Silco is dead.
底城现在群龙无首
The underground, leaderless.
如果按照你们的想法办
If we follow your plan,
反而可能令他们团结起来
we risk unifying them against us.
那你的高见是什么
So, what is your solution?
是公开声讨 还是严厉斥责
Chastisement? A firm reprimand?
把罪责都推到金克丝身上
We use their division against them.
让他们产生分歧
Pin the attack on Jinx,
重金悬赏 开出他们无法拒绝的价码
post a reward too substantial to ignore.
很抱歉 梅尔
I'm sorry, Mel.
拿我们的命运去做赌注 我觉得不妥
I'm not comfortable trusting our fates to chance.
金克丝从来就不可控
Jinx has proven elusive.
只有将她绳之以法
Our healing can only begin
我们的伤痛才能被彻底终结
once she's been brought to justice.
结论很明显了
Then it's settled,
二比一
2 to 1.
主动出击
We invade.
请听我说一句
If I may?
面对这样的局面
In crises such as these,
当务之急是统一意见 给民众一个交代
it's imperative you present a unified front to the public,
个人感受先放一边
whatever your personal feelings.
真知灼见啊
How wise.
我赞成下令主动出击
I'll agree to endorse the invasion.
但我反对利用海克斯科技
But I draw the line at Hextech.
这点上早有共识
We have an ethos.
不到万不得已 不能动用这种武力
Such force must be a final resort.
完全同意
Agreed.
结论很明显了
Then it's settled,
二比一
2 to 1.
我本来有机会的
I had the shot.
这是你母亲留给你的
Your mother left this to you.
吉拉曼恩家族钥匙
The Kiramman Key?
不 我还没…
No, I'm not…
我根本不配
I don't deserve it.
以后就交给你了 凯特琳
It's your legacy now, Caitlyn.
她为什么还在这儿
What is she still doing here?
嘿
Hey.
你说得对 凯特琳
You were right, Cait.
她不是爆爆了
Powder's gone.
我有办法补救
I can make this right.
如果你能说服杰斯修好拳套
If you get Jayce to fix the gauntlets,
我自己一个人去 就不会再害得别人受伤了
I can do this myself. No one else needs to get hurt.
不
No.
不要再轻举妄动
No more rogue mission.
也不要再意气用事
No more reckless plans.
我妈妈说得对
My mother was right.
我总是自以为是 爱逞强
My arrogance led me to take on more than I could handle,
结果…
and
让她赔上了性命
she paid the price.
他们要派执法官追捕金克丝
They're sending all the Enforcers after Jinx.
我会一起去
I'm going with them.
让我去 让我做点什么
Please, I have to help.
可以啊
You can.
来加入我们
As one of us.
凯特琳 这东西我没法戴
Cait, I can't wear this.
民众要求血债血偿
People are calling for blood.
议会不会阻拦
The Council won't stop them.
并非每个底城人都支持金克丝
You can show that not all of Zaun supports Jinx.
我们一起
We can show them.
证明这点
Together.
他们在我的面前杀死了我的父母
I watched them kill my parents.
你懂那是种什么感觉吗
Do you have any idea how that feels?
我懂 我都懂
Yes. I do.
我本以为我们是一边的
I thought you were on our side.
你根本就没有考虑过我
You didn't think at all.
怎么回事儿
Hey, watch it.
抱歉
Sorry.
也不是头一回了
Not my first.
你没事吧
You all right?
那场袭击 你也有亲人遇难了
You, uh… lose someone in the attack?
他怎么样了
How is he?
跟之前一样 有呼吸
Same as before. Breathing.
脉搏稳定
Pulse is consistent.
除此之外
Beyond that,
我知道的也不比你多
your guess is good as mine.
这东西把他怎么了
What's it doing to him?
海克斯核心在不断进化
The Hexcore has been evolving.
符文样式瞬息万变 我都跟不上了
Shifting through runic patterns faster than I can keep up.
我只能确定它维持着他的生命
All I know for certain is that it's keeping him alive.
这种谜题他最感兴趣 只可惜…
It's the sort of puzzle Viktor would love if he wasn't…
受伤的人应该是我才对
It should be me up there instead of him.
别这么说
Don't say that.
他会好起来的
He'll come back to us.
我怎么都想不通
I still don't understand.
他当时就在我旁边
He was right next to me.
为什么爆炸把他炸成这样 而我却…
How does the explosion do that to him, and I just…?
而我却毫发无伤 安然无恙
I just walk out without a scratch?
有些事是没有道理的 杰斯
There's no sense to these things, Jayce.
议会那边怎么样了
How'd it go with the Council?
我母亲也参与进来了
My mother's entered the game.
她成功取得了萨罗的信任
She's already gotten her hooks into Salo.
表面上像是帮他
Using his grief to make a play
但心里只有海克斯科技
for Hextech.
梅尔 我答应过维克托
Mel, I promised Viktor,
再也不会…
never again.
别担心 我已经解决了
It's all right. I handled it.
我不会让他们毁掉你的梦想
I won't let them corrupt your dream.
凯特琳当时也在
Caitlyn was there.
你是不是该去看看她
You might pay her a visit.
这姑娘虽然极力掩饰
She hides it admirably,
但心里一定很难受
but the poor girl's in so much pain.
嘿 小豆芽
Hey, Sprout.
你怎么找来的
How'd you find me?
你爸说的
Your dad.
妈妈和我想清净的时候常来这儿
Mother and I used to come here when we needed an escape.
也是我们难得不吵架的地方
One of the few places we never argued.
真对不起 我现在才来
I'm sorry I haven't been around.
维克托怎么样了
How's Viktor?
我都不确定他是不是活着
I can't even tell if he's still in there.
那次袭击后
Ever since it happened…
有三张面孔不停地在我脑子里打转
three faces keep spinning through my mind.
我看见我妈妈她死时的样子
I see Mother. When they found her.
我整个人就开始往下沉
And every fiber of me just sinks,
像一块石头被黑水吞没
like a stone swallowed in dark water.
然后我看到了金克丝 她在笑
But then there's Jinx. Laughing.
我想掐住她的喉咙
I want to tear that laugh
让她再也笑不出来
from her throat forever.
凯特琳
Cait.
我知道
I know.
我现在才明白要恨一个人有多容易
I just understand now how easy it is to hate them.
一次恶行就够了
One vicious act.
我还看见了蔚
Then I see Vi.
我想要拉她当执法官
I asked her to put on the uniform.
不说也知道 她没有答应
Suffice to say, she declined.
蔚 当执法官
Vi? Wear a badge?
她以为只要有你那副拳套
She thinks those gauntlets of yours will solve
就能解决一切问题
all her problems.
如果她是对的呢
What if she's right?
海克斯科技或许可以保命
Hextech may keep us alive, Jayce,
但问题仍然无法根除
but it's not what will save us.
我
Me.
加入那群虾兵蟹将
Join the peanut patrol. Ha.
我还以为她没什么幽默感呢
And I thought she had no sense of humor.
虾酱 好吃
I like peanuts.
她爸说得对
Her dad's right.
确实没有必要再待在这儿了
There's no point in sticking around up here.
只是 是我制造出了那个怪物
Except… I'm the one who created the monster.
蔚
Vi?
你谁啊
Who are you?
你怎么知道我叫蔚啊
And how do you know my name?
我是初级执法官诺伦…
Junior Officer Nolen.
麦迪
Maddie.
那个…
And, uh…
你脸上不是写着嘛
it's written on your face.
有什么事儿吗
So, what is it?
随机抽查 还是要强制驱逐
Random search? Escort off the property?
不会只是想要浪费我的时间吧
Or you just here to waste my time?
抽查 不是
Search? No.
不 你在…
No, no. Heh.
在执法官之间可是个传奇人物
Uh, you're something of a legend amongst the Enforcers.
有人反对你的加入
Caitlyn made quite a scene at the station
凯特琳为此大闹了一场
when they tried to deny your enlistment.
我必须得问问
Now I have to ask,
是真的吗
is it all true?
不靠议会 你单枪匹马就去追希尔科去了
You went after Silco alone when the Council wouldn't back you?
挑他们一群人
Took on his whole gang?
这是她说的
Cait said all that?
她还说要是执法官都有你这种胆量
She said if every Enforcer had a heart like yours,
我们就能对付诺克萨斯了
we could take on Noxus itself.
她还拿她们家撤资当要挟
Then she threatened to withdraw her family's funding.
总之欢迎你加入
Anyhow, I'm glad you're joining up.
自打长官变节后
After the sheriff betrayed
我…
us…
这么说吧
Well, let's just say…
知道这儿还有好人
it's nice to know there
多少能得到些安慰
are still good ones left.
我要去巡逻了
Duty calls.
很高兴认识你
A real honor, Vi.
成为议员的众多特权之一就是
One of the many privileges of serving as your councilor
可以时不时地 站上这个讲台 为民众发声
is having the occasion now and again to stand behind this podium
今天我们相聚一堂
to behold so many
不是因为出身或义务在身
joined together not by birth
而是因为我们有共同点
or dictum but by all that we share.
我们的希望
Our hope.
我们的好奇心
Our curiosity.
以及我们身上背负的
Our compulsion to leave behind us
想留下一个更好世界的使命
a world better than that before.
正是这些共同点
These things we share are
才让我们能够团结一心
what make us one people.
今天
Today
我们在这里
we share an
一起沉痛悼念
unthinkable loss.
伊利乌斯波尔波克议员
Councilor Irius Bolbok,
托曼霍斯卡尔议员
Councilor Torman Hoskel,
以及卡桑德拉吉拉曼恩议员
and Councilor Cassandra Kiramman
离开了我们
were taken from us.
他们会被永远铭记
But they shall not be forgotten.
我们建造雕像的初衷
We commissioned this statue
是为了铭记他们的丰功伟绩
so we may remember them for their countless contributions…
纪念他们毕生的付出
their lifetimes of service.
而不是记录夺取他们生命的卑劣行为
Not for the craven act that stole them away.
喂 干什么
Ma'am, you can't go in…
我们遭到了沉重的打击
Though we've suffered a terrible blow,
但我向你们保证
I assure you,
在皮尔特沃夫 我们执法必严
the rule of law prevails in Piltover.
- 不… - 我们必将缉拿施暴者
- No. - We will find those responsible.
并让他们付出应有的代价
And they will account for their crimes.
滋味不好受吧
Awful, isn't it?
失去所爱之人
Losing a loved one.
别以为住在上城就安全了
You aren't safe up here, toppers.
谁都跑不了
None of you are safe.
走啊
Go.
你快带议员离开 我有个主意
Get the counselors out of here. I have an idea.
你要干什么去
What are you doing?
替我儿子偿命
For my son.
来吧
Come on.
该死
Shit.
都解决了
Perimeter secured.
看吧
We'll see.
我还以为你这次死定了呢
Thought you were gonna get yourself killed.
这是追思会
A memorial.
没事了
I got you.
他们简直不是人
What kind of animals?
他们就想把事情闹大
They wanted the spectacle.
就想让你们害怕
They're trying to scare you.
我只觉得怒不可遏
All they did is piss me off.
你…
You…
你得想个办法让他们取消这次行动
You need to find a way to call off the invasion.
什么
What?
今天这一仗都已经这么惨了
This battle was on your soil.
到了那边可就是他们说了算了
Down there, you'll be on their terms.
都到这份上了
没什么是我们能说了算的
None of this is on our terms.
也许你该想想办法
Maybe you should change that.
那你说有什么办法 你说
I don't know how, okay?
她死了 留下一个这么大的窟窿
She dies and leaves this giant hole,
就好像该我来补
and I'm just supposed to fill it.
仿佛她的努力都毫无意义
Like she was never there to begin with.
补不上的
Hey. You won't.
窟窿会变小 但是…
The hole gets smaller, but…
永远补不好
you never fill it.
我不该把徽章塞给你的
I was wrong to spring the badge on you.
只是…
It's just…
不管我怎么做
every way I slice it,
如果我跟你妹妹碰上
if I go after your sister alone,
不是她死 就是我亡
one of us comes back in a box.
无可挽回了
It's all coming apart.
可以挽回的
No, it isn't.
只要我们一起
We won't let it.
我知道你对自己 与生俱来的权力很介怀
I know you doubt the merit of your birthright, Caitlyn.
你也有你的道理
There's wisdom in that.
可是要记住
But remember:
你姓吉拉曼恩
You're a Kiramman.
皮尔特沃夫的历史上
Never in our lifetimes has Piltover's
还从来没有出现过议员 被迫躲进地牢开议会这种事
leadership been forced into the dungeons of our capitol.
看看我们现在
But here we are.
现在还有人觉得
Does anyone still doubt
我们的敌人只是一个 精神错乱的疯子吗
that our enemy is greater than one deranged individual?
他们是怎么让那些怪物潜入会场的
How did they sneak so many of these things into the ceremony?
我还以为我们的安保措施万无一失
I thought we took every measure to secure it.
他们一定有内应
They must have had help.
大概率是上城的人
From someone up here.
我们不能再坐以待毙了
We can't afford any more handwringing.
再不启用海克斯科技来保命
If we do not defend ourselves with Hextech,
所有的原则都将毫无意义
our principles will mean nothing.
我…
I…
我们还没有做好全面出击的准备
We aren't prepared for a full-scale invasion.
这次袭击就是证明
The undercity's attack proved that.
这是议员的内部会议
This is a closed Council meeting.
谁让你进来的
Who let you in here?
我既是有功勋的执法官
I am a decorated officer.
也是吉拉曼恩家的当家人
Leader of House Kiramman.
要么对我尊重点 要么就把嘴给我闭上
Address me with respect, or keep your mouth shut.
我会带突击队去底城完成三项任务
I will lead a strike team into Zaun with three objectives:
找到金克丝
locate Jinx,
摧毁微光
dismantle Shimmer,
铲除所有效忠于希尔科的残党余孽
and neutralize any agents still loyal to Silco.
你凭什么觉得自己 比其他的战士们出色呢
What makes you think you'll fare better than our forces today?
我们自有办法出奇制胜
We've got a few surprises of our own.
（进化人物）
字幕翻译： 付博文 韩一旻